Jake Hui Wang

Woodside, NY, 11377 | 646-206-5709 | huiwang339@gmail.com

Github: mypwhas9letters | LinkedIn | jakeww.com

Full Stack Web Developer

Full-stack web developer with experience building applications in JavaScript, React, and Ruby on Rails. Possess strong skills in problem-solving and analyzing data that will help software organizations further their success. I want to utilize my passion to learn the latest technologies to grow as a developer while helping your organization advance in the software engineering industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python, Microsoft Office, G Suite

EXPERIENCE

Campaign Tech Specialist, Digidems, Virginia Beach, Virginia

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

- Directed cybersecurity training and integrated best computer safety practices into the workflow to minimize the risk of hacking.
- Utilized Microsoft Excel and Google Sheets for creating tools to analyze and track data from Field Organizers.
- Designed and developed web applications for voter outreach and campaign finance reporting.
- Resolved network, hardware, software, security, printing, and general computer issues.
- Trained volunteers to use phone-banking tools and managed hundreds of volunteers on the Hustle texting program.

Data Specialist, **Heart To Heart Home Care**, Brooklyn, New York

Jan 2015 - Jun 2017

- Developed and designed reports, reporting tools, and dashboards using advanced Microsoft Excel techniques.
- Processed, tracked, and fixed any discrepancies in payroll for thousands of employees and multi-million dollars in billing claims weekly.
- Provided IT support ranging from troubleshooting software issues to resolving hardware problems.
- Analyzed data and accurately developed reporting procedures to evaluate the company's performance.

Data Analyst, J&JC Beer Distribution, Elmhurst, New York

Sep 2012 - Jan 2015

- Generated revenue reports, created invoices, processed orders, and maintained daily records of sales.
- Monitored the sales team metrics, provided support, and identified inefficiencies based on productivity scores of each sales representative.
- Explored opportunities to improve processes in the development of ad-hoc reports, analytical tools, and data analysis.
- Supervised inventory control, coordinated deliveries, and handled communication with suppliers.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

NPM simple-react-google-maps - Github | Link

Google Maps React.is Component

- Created an open-source NPM package for React is applications.
- Allow developers to quickly and simply render Google Maps in their projects.

Parallel - Github | Link

An Airbnb-like full-stack web application for parking cars

- Developed and designed a single-page application with React for the front-end and Redux for state management.
- Built a RESTful backend server using Ruby on Rails and managed data storage with PostgresSQL.
- Implemented an authentication and authorization system with JWT tokens to secure user's data.
- Designed the application following the Model View Controller (MVC) software architectural pattern.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School. New York. New York

Nov 2017

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Program

Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York

May 2012